♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 14]
The testimonies they gave before
were all fake.
They might recant them
if they were sent
to the Ministry of Justice.
Hence, Li Chengze
decided to silence them.
Everything
adds up by now.
Exactly.
Fortunately, the truth is revealed.
Fan Wujiu is a brilliant pawn
that can be used against his owner.
But there is something I don't get.
Why would he show up there?
I don't get it either.
I swear to Heaven,
Fan Wujiu has already left the Capital
for another mission.
Besides, you knew
that I suggested the Ministry of Justice
take the culprits away.
If I were the culprit,
isn't that extra work?
I'm confused.
To be honest,
I'm confused too.
Wait.
Is Fan Wujiu dead?
No.
They captured him alive.
Everything will be all right, then.
So as long Fan Wujiu admits
that you sent him out of the Capital,
your suspicion could be cleared.
But he can't admit that.
The public mustn't know
that Second Prince sent him
to assassinate Fan Sizhe.
Besides,
Fan Sizhe was traveling
with the members
of the Imperial Inspectorate.
Killing the authority equals treason.
If I were Fan Wujiu,
I had better keep my mouth shut.
After all,
killing a murderer is better
than treason.
Did you send Fan Sizhe away?
Yes.
Did you plan this
when you sent him away?
No.
I couldn't have seen this coming.
I was thinking
that the Second Prince
wouldn't let him pass easily
since he was involved
in the Baoyue Pleasure House.
I just considered more
for his safety.
Judging by Fan Wujiu's skills,
ordinary ninth-ranked guards
couldn't hold him down.
Indeed.
Who could capture him, then?
Needless to say,
it must be someone exceptional.
What is this place?
You had killed lives
in the Capital Magistrate's presence.
Is it fun playing dumb here?
Kill lives?
Why?
Are you trying
to deny the solid evidence?
[Haitang Duoduo,
Northern Qi Holy Maiden]
What a surprise.
To think that Northern Qi Hold Maiden
is protecting a Qing man.
A Qing is killing another Qing.
The Qi might as well play along.
Play along, you say?
You would like to play along.
Having a duel
with the Northern Qi Holy Maiden
makes my years of practice
worthwhile!
For real?
You may kill, but never insult me!
The defeat was well-earned.
This is just a normal cooperation.
Haitang Duoduo and I
are not related in any way.
I haven't said anything yet.
I know what you are thinking.
I have the responsibility to say
that you got the wrong idea.
Continue if you wish.
I will even swear to Heaven!
Who am I to Wan'er?
You are her father.
If so, do you think
I should believe you?
You shouldn't doubt my character.
Didn't you entrust the Lin family
and Wan'er to me
because you believe I'm honest?
This is the Capital.
Do I dare to trust
someone honest?
But I'm clear and innocent.
Are you not going to trust me, then?
Your shamelessness
is the hope of our Lin family
in the future.
Is that
a compliment or an insult?
A compliment, of course.
It was a masterstroke
to tackle Fan Wujiu.
The death warriors, slander, culprit,
and all the schemes
have been overturned by now.
In this round,
Li Chengze is showing signs of defeat.
You are here.
We don't have much time.
So make it quick.
Tell me what happened.
I was trying to kill Fan Sizhe
inside Northern Qi.
Haitang Duoduo stepped in
and I lost.
They escorted me back to the Capital
and detained me for a few days.
I was knocked out this morning.
When I woke up,
I found myself
in front of the Capital Magistrate.
Haitang Duoduo escorted you back here?
It wasn't her.
It was the Imperial Inspectorate.
Imperial Inspectorate?
Do you know what the situation is now?
I'm not sure.
But don't worry.
My lips are sealed.
I won't reveal anything.
His Highness prepared those murderers
to use against Fan Xian.
But then, your appearance
has driven His Highness to a dead end.
Will I be killed?
You can't die just yet.
What should I do next?
First,
don't bring up
the assassination of Fan Sizhe.
Understood.
Second,
find another reason for the assassination
in front of the Capital Magistrate.
Don't get His Highness involved.
With my current identity,
they won't believe everything I say.
It doesn't matter
whether they believe it or not.
Only a workable reason is needed.
Sure.
All right.
I will do it.
Not much time is left.
Is there anything else you want to say?
I will relay it to His Highness.
Xie,
did I lose my chance
to sit for the spring exam?
Thank His Highness on my behalf.
At least he gave me hope.
Tell him that I'm thankful.
I should get going.
Xie.
Please do me a favor.
Go on.
Bring me a book.
Just one.
I want classics.
Any book will do.
Thank you.
His Highness predicted that.
[Book of Documents]
He knows me the best.
Tell His Highness
that I'm grateful to him.
How did they treat you?
Do you have meat?
Haitang Duoduo
and the Imperial Inspectorate
are on Fan Xian's side.
Is something going on
between Haitang Duoduo and Fan Xian?
I don't think so.
Then, why did she help him?
Because Fan Xian
is the future owner
of the Imperial Treasury.
[Shangjing City, capital of Northern Qi]
Holy Maiden,
thank you for rescuing me
in desperate times like that.
Is it all right?
Yes.
All right.
Wait. What are you talking about?
The Shangjing City.
Yes, of course.
How does it compare to the Capital
of the Qing State?
They are unique in their own way.
Why are you covering your face?
Don't do that.
I'm afraid people might recognize me.
People in both states
look almost the same.
Don't worry. They can't tell the difference
by looking at faces.
Put it down.
It's not that.
Do you know
how famous I am in the Qing State?
My father is Fan Jian.
The Minister of Revenue.
Earl Sinan.
Imagine how dangerous I can be
as the child of a dignitary
in a foreign land.
I'm starting to admire
the Fan family now.
Thank you,
Sister-in-law.
Hold on.
What did you just call me?
Ha! You like that.
But I can only call you that here.
Sister-in-law.
What did Fan Xian tell you about me?
He needn't tell me anything.
The entire Qing State knows.
I understand.
You understand, my foot.
Listen,
this is the Qi.
Don't talk nonsense.
Stop calling me that.
We have to keep it on the down-low here?
No!
Gone public already?
I have nothing to do with Fan Xian.
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
Well, Sister-in-law,
you need not hide it from me.
I'm on your side.
You have my support.
What nonsense are you saying?
You haven't seen another sister-in-law
back in the Capital.
She is so weak
and lacks energy.
She is like Daiyu from "Red Mansion."
Unlike you,
you are well-built...
I'm telling you.
I helped Fan Xian
mainly because he would take over
the Imperial Treasury.
The two states
have some business.
Do you understand?
If
a civil strife breaks up
in the Qing State,
I will be happy to see that. Understood?
So
you just won't believe me?
Come on.
Where are we going, Sister-in-law?
[Oil Store]
Here we are.
Go inside.
This is Qing's store
in the Shangjing City.
What is this for?
Command center of spies.
Fan Xian wanted me to bring you here.
Command center of spies?
Exactly.
He even told you a place like this?
I know you both are...
Good friends.
I have done my bit here.
You are on your own now.
[Cold Medicine]
Is anyone here?
I caught a cold.
I'm not serving today.
Please help yourself.
Guo Baokun.
[Guo Baokun, spy stationed in the Qi]
Fan Sizhe?
You...
Wait.
That's medicine.
Where is Fan Xian?
At home, maybe. I don't know.
What are you doing here instead?
I'm here to offer help.
You can't be serious.
Do you know what this place is?
All undercover spies of the Qing State
are under my command.
Don't interfere
with an important task like this.
Why can't I come here when you are here?
Jeez.
Do you know Yan Bingyun?
Yes. He serves in the Fourth Division
of the Imperial Inspectorate.
Even a figure like him
made a mistake in Northern Qi.
Look at me.
Under my deployment,
this little store is safe,
as if it hides deeply in a chasm.
The disguise is simply flawless.
Do you still
underestimate me?
You are really good
at eating, Duoduo.
Yogurt and fruits are the perfect pair.
Lang Tao,
what brings you here?
[Lang Tao, disciple of Grandmaster Ku He]
His Majesty sends me here.
He wants to know
if Fan Sizhe has been sent
to Guo Baokun's oil store.
Does His Majesty know
about the oil store too?
Not only him
but also all officials in the court.
Even
our reclusive master
knows about it.
His Majesty says
he likes Guo Baokun.
He mustn't leave.
Too bad if a smart one replaces him.
That's easy.
Just pretend we know nothing about it.
That's difficult!
Pretending to overlook
a careless
and glaringly illogical mistake
is a way too difficult thing to do.
Don't worry.
As long as the whole state
pulls our weight.
We must keep Guo Baokun here.
In my eyes, the Embroidered Uniform Guards
of Northern Qi are like weaklings.
The spy network of Shangjing City
works perfectly well
under my current charge.
Let me put it this way.
The imperial guards don't come here
when they patrol.
You see,
I have concealed myself so well.
That sounds impressive.
But it doesn't feel right.
Why not?
Speak up. Just say it.
Everything feels right.
Since Fan Xian entrusted you to me,
I would do him this favor.
You should learn and observe more.
How about this?
You will go with us
for the next outing.
What?
Outing?
With whom?
The spies.
Do you spies go on outings?
What's wrong with that?
We are far away from our hometown
in this dangerous place.
Naturally, we have fear and worry.
So I thought
we could gather for an outing or a meal
when we have time.
We can also read books together.
Well... What if, I mean if.
What if the Northern Qi
catches you in one fell swoop
while you are having a gathering?
No one has ever noticed us.
As you can see,
I was born to be a spy.
Fan Xian is so lucky to have me.
Lucky him.
It's a shame that you are going back.
Where?
Back to the Capital.
Fan Xian sent me here
to take you back.
Why?
I don't know.
He mentioned he promised you
to save your father.
Really?
He said now is the right time.
Did he give me an order?
I don't know. Ask him yourself.
What about this place?
Are you taking over?
What's wrong with me taking over?
All I do is take them out
for outings and gatherings, right?
But
I need to send you back first.
All right.
What is this?
What are you doing?
We have a lot of time.
I'm packing my things.
We can set off now.
Shouldn't we do some planning?
What is there to plan?
We have plenty of time on the way
to think about it.
Never let our enemies predict our move.
As long as we are quick enough,
we can catch them off guard.
Guo Baokun and Fan Sizhe
left the oil store
and headed out of the city
with a baggage?
Yes, they were spotted
the moment they left.
We are all watching.
Are they going back to the Qing State?
It seems so.
What now?
Should we let them go?
Don't ask me.
Why don't you ask
His Majesty?
He said he wanted to keep Guo Baokun.
According to His Majesty,
you decide how to deal
with Fan Sizhe and Guo Baokun.
Is anyone replacing Guo Baokun?
No. They left suddenly.
I think we should just let them go.
It's pointless keeping them.
At least we can leave a good impression.
Who knows?
He might come back here again.
I don't care. I'm just a messenger.
You decide.
You all should cherish me
as the Holy Maiden.
Don't make me do everything
and enjoy your time idly.
I'm the Holy Maiden, you know?
Idly?
[*Idle and Fan Xian's name sound alike]
By the way,
His Majesty wants you
to write to Fan Xian.
Why?
It has been some time
since he returned to the Southern Qing,
yet he has stopped updating
"Red Mansion".
This isn't good.
All you know is read books.
Let them go.
Yes.
I will go and check on them.
Why doesn't he write? Why me?
Because of Fan Xian.
What about him?
You and him
get along quite well.
We...
We get along well, my foot!
Duoduo, you are the Holy Maiden.
Do mind your language.
I have nothing
to do with him.
It's like I have something
You people!
I...
Argh!
Duoduo, remember to write to him.
Tell him to update.
Vegetables for sale!
Vegetables!
Make ways.
Holy Maiden.
How's it?
They act weirdly along the way.
Many people are suspecting them.
But we have already handled it.
Where did they get the carriage?
They rented it.
Where is their destination?
The border.
Did they say that directly?
Didn't think of switching
to another carriage halfway?
Not at all.
The owner of the carriage service
immediately reported to the official,
but we stopped him.
Holy Maiden,
should we escort them
to Southern Qing safely?
Yes.
If so, we have to follow them
all the way.
Tough days for you all.
All clear.
That was smart.
You told him you wanted
to go to the border,
not the Qing State.
Laying low
is the first rule of being a spy.
I'm pretty gifted, right?
Sizhe,
looks like
you have potential in this.
Guo,
I was rude to you before.
It wasn't until today
that I realized why
Fan Xian
dared leave you
in the Northern Qi alone.
Having talents like us,
the Qing State will eventually
take over the world.
Hear, hear!
Mr. Fan,
two news.
First,
Fan Wujiu
has already confessed
to the Ministry of Justice.
What did he say?
I serve the Second Prince.
Yuan Meng and Prince Jing
know each other,
and Prince Jing frequents
His Highness' place.
That's how I got to know Yuan Meng.
When Yuan Meng offers her service
at the Baoyue Pleasure House,
I saw an opportunity in this
and secretly helped
the Baoyue Pleasure House
with the indenture matters
behind His Highness' back.
Unfortunately, someone found out.
So I hired hitmen,
which then
led to the murder.
I was being too greedy.
It was all done by me.
His confession is quite conclusive.
He took all the blame for it.
He said
he used your name to hire hitmen
in an attempt to plant the crime on you.
This doesn't make any sense.
If he used my name to hire the hitmen,
why did he kill them?
Those murderers left a trail
leading to him,
so he had no choice but to kill them.
However,
his confession
has cleared your suspicions.
I was worried
he might smear you
for being an accomplice.
The Second Prince and I
are at each other's throats,
no one would believe his guard
conspired with me.
As of now, Fan Wujiu
can't even help himself.
He can only cut any possible ties
with the Second Prince.
Is that really manageable?
That will be the day!
People here know too much
to pull the wool over their eyes.
But the Ministry of Justice
didn't question his confession.
They just turn a blind eye
despite knowing the truth.
You said there were two news.
What about the second news?
You have another visitor.
I'm seriously ill. I'm not available.
It's Lai Mingcheng
of the Imperial Procuratorate.
That fellow who impeached me last time?
Yes, it's him.
He came to visit me.
What is he up to?
Mr. Fan
is severely ill.
But when he knew you came,
he insisted on seeing you.
How big is your house?
My house?
The Fan's Residence.
Fan's Residence, well...
I'm not sure.
The size of the officials' residence
is restricted according to their rank.
If the Fan's Residence exceeds that,
I must impeach him.
Maybe you can measure the place.
I'm not prepared today.
Do you have a ruler?
One moment. I will bring you one.
There is no need for that.
Wouldn't it take too long
if I measured alone?
I don't know.
No one has done this before.
Do you need my help?
Not for today.
Next time.
Mr. Fan, why did you get up?
I asked you to rest in the bed.
Mr. Fan.
You are here, Mr. Lai.
Mr. Lai,
I'm weak,
so I won't stand up.
Mr. Fan, I have asked
the imperial physician.
He said you are seriously injured.
So I bought you some red dates.
It's good for your blood circulation.
Thank you so much.
We censors
are only paid chump change,
unlike those officials.
You probably have heard
that within the Capital Magistrate,
we censors are the poorest.
I wanted to buy some supplementary
for you.
But I can't afford that.
Please understand.
Red dates are good.
I like red dates.
Please sit, Mr. Lai.
Wang,
serve the tea.
It won't take long.
Please have a seat.
Let me pour for you.
Mr. Fan.
Your father is poisoned,
and you are seriously injured.
Is this the Second Prince's doing?
All I can say is
I have no proof.
It's hard to say.
Have you heard
about Fan Wujiu's statement?
I did.
He is merely a retainer,
yet he had the nerves to be involved
in the Baoyue Pleasure House murder case
behind His Highness' back.
That just sounds nonsense.
So?
So I want to impeach the Second Prince.
You
want to impeach the prince?
We are censors.
We should uphold our integrity
and speak against evil.
May I ask
why you are telling me this?
Since
the corruption investigation started,
all names on that list
have been officials in the Capital
connected to the Second Prince.
If we were to dig deeper
to the core,
the Imperial Procuratorate alone
isn't enough.
So you are suggesting
that you can't continue anymore?
Unless the Imperial Inspectorate
could provide us
with related case files.
Are you seeking my help?
Not you.
I'm proposing a collaboration
with the Imperial Inspectorate.
If so, you should go there.
What are you doing here at my place?
I don't know anyone
in the Imperial Inspectorate,
but you.
I just impeached you.
We can be considered as acquaintances.
What kind of acquaintance is this?
The corruption investigation
is for the sake of the state.
Is that a problem?
If I agree to help you,
will you still impeach me?
Of course I will.
You are demanding my help
when you will impeach me afterward?
This isn't a personal grudge.
You can mix business
with personal affairs.
The state law is strict.
How could it be a personal favor?
It's like you will bite the hand
that feeds you.
Forget it if you don't want to help.
I will.
Sorry?
I will collaborate with you.
Wang.
Bring Mr. Lai
to the Imperial Inspectorate.
He can access any related documents
in the First Division.
All right.
Mr. Fan,
you are different from what I imagined.
Mr. Lai,
even though you have impeached me
and may do so again,
I have a feeling that one day
we might become friends.
That's impossible.
Officials shouldn't have personal relationships.
You are right.
However,
Mr. Fan,
we might collaborate
on the corruption investigation.
For the sake of the state.
There is something I would like to ask.
When will you recover?
Why?
After you recover,
I'm going to impeach you
for the Baoyue Pleasure House case.
How long will you need to finish
the documents in the First Division?
One day should be enough.
Two days. I will attend
the court session two days after.
You will recover in two days?
Since I have accepted your dates,
I shouldn't delay you.
Well, then.
See you in the court
in two days.
He amazed me.
I will see him off.
As expected of you.
The Imperial Procuratorate
just impeached you,
and here comes the second impeachment.
You even got me involved.
What an interesting experience
for an official.
Indeed.
Other officials seek friends,
but I seek trouble.
You do know that.
It's my fault.
Says who?
Those who harm lives or break the laws
are to blame.
Troubles always surround
honest men.
I fear anything
but not trouble.
Are you all right?
Never mind me.
As long as both of you recover.
Why is he even talking to you?
What's wrong?
Ever since Lai Mincheng became a censor,
he has been like a mad dog
that bites and never smiles.
I have never seen him greeting anyone.
I quite appreciate Mr. Lai
as an official.
The sky is getting cloudy.
[Hanmo Hall]
It's the sign of rain.
Let's move. His Majesty is waiting.
This isn't the way to the main hall.
We are meeting
at the Imperial Study today.
Why? Shouldn't it be in the main hall?
His Majesty said
the Imperial Procuratorate's target
is you.
You are only a minor official.
You don't deserve to use the main hall
and waste the officials' time.
Fine, I don't deserve that.
Where should I sit?
Sit?
Stand at the back.
Not only Mr. Fan.
I can't believe
the Imperial Procuratorate is bold.
Coming through. Make way.
Excuse me.
Everyone is flustered.
Indeed.
Tell me about it.
Mr. Xin.
Mr. Fan.
Why are you hiding here?
Uh... I'm looking at books.
This is a good hiding place.
No one could see us.
I have a question.
Why are there so many people here?
His Majesty said
this meeting isn't compulsory.
Attendance is voluntary.
Voluntary?
But almost everyone is here.
Don't take the word "voluntary"
too seriously.
Look over there.
They are all here.
No one dares skip the meeting.
Right?
His Majesty has arrived.
This isn't like the main hall.
No need to stand on ceremony.
Do sit down.
Just relax.
Fan Xian.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Lai Mingcheng.
Do you still
want to impeach him?
Yes.
Not only him
but also the Minister of Revenue,
Fan Jian.
Your Majesty,
before Mr. Lai begins,
may I propose my impeachment?
Go on.
Please look at this, Your Majesty.
They are all precious jewels.
I had them appraised.
They are very valuable.
Where did you get this?
A few days ago, Princess Lin and I
visited a senior.
He gave us this as a gift.
Even a casual gift
could be so valuable.
There are more in his house.
His residence is built on the mountain.
He gathers various rare jewels
from the world
and has countless courtesans.
Such extravagance is unbelievable.
Who is this person, then?
Director of the Imperial Inspectorate,
Chen Pingping.
This is outrageous!
I accuse Chen Pingping
of corruption and bribery.
Please investigate him thoroughly,
Your Majesty.
Mr. Chen.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Any explanation?
Mr. Fan,
is it wrong
that I gave away my own things?
I don't have a say in this.
The thing is, the court
is investigating corruption
to preserve clear governance
and strengthen law enforcement.
At this point,
I wouldn't dare to accept gifts.
Your Majesty,
may I explain myself?
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪